Jake Knowles

Front End Developer Born 1994 in London



About me

Enthusiastic and creative front-end developer with over 5 years of experience. I am knowledgeable in a range of front-end languages and tools to build and maintain a wide range of web applications although I am always keen to learn new skills and languages.

Skills



Contact



iakeyknowles@hotmail.co.uk



(7) jknowles94

Projects

Centurions Major Golf App React & Node

An ongoing project which tracks events from golf tournaments with stats and a leaderboard. It is built using the latest version of React using hooks.



Experience

Lead Front-End Developer

Amigo Partnership Since March 2020

Remotely lead the front-end team of 4 to deliver high end websites and apps for a range of clients, mainly using React, Next.js and Angular 8 with Capacitor. Most of our projects had to integrate with headless Content Management Systems including CraftCMS and wordpress API. Since my arrival, I have implemented a more collaborative working environment, using Pull Requests and code reviews. Now all our new projects, depending on client requests, will use Next.js with Typescript and TailwindCSS.

Front-End Developer

IPUSHPULL

April 2019 - March 2020

Migrated the main web app from AngularJS to Vue and build a reusable component architecture to use throughout other intergrations such as Symphony and Microsoft Teams. Implement a continuous integration while running tests using Cypress and Bitbucket Pipelines.

Front-End Developer

Amigo Partnership

August 2015 - April 2019

I was working in a small development team of 6 to create and develop a bespoke CMS using AngularJS and our own API using GraphQL/Rails. I am responsible for leading a team to deliver a bespoke CMS and web app (including a native app, using Cordova), on a range of clients, such as, Rolls-Royce, O2 and Xcina. I am assisting with the growth of the company, to help improve the workflow and production throughout the development team in order to work more efficiently.

Junior Front-End and Email Developer

Mccormack & Morrison

October 2013 - July 2015

Building and maintaining websites and landing pages for companies using wordpress. Creating responsive emails and newsletters that work over multiple platforms.

Web Developer Apprentice

Contentive

September 2012 - October 2013

Building, testing and maintaining business standard websites for clients including Landing pages and HTML Email Templates.



Education

IT Professional (Web Development) August 2012 - August 2013 Level 3 Diploma

ICT- BTEC National, History, Media Studies September 2010 - May 2012 A Level